# **Azmine Toushik Wasi**

+880 1521 526792 | <u>azminetoushik.wasi@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Kaggle</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Website</u>

#### Summery

An idealist with distinguished experience, and expertise in Programming, IT Automation, Product Development and Project Management. Currently, exploring Data Science, Machine Learning and IT Automation. Love to learn new things, improve existing skills, experiment with acquired skills and challenge my capabilities.

#### **Technical Skills**

Programming Skills: Python (Advanced), R, C

Kaggle Dataset

Data Related Skills: Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, SAS Visual Business Analytics, SQL, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Machine Learning Skills: Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, Pycaret

#### **Education**

Feb 2020 - Present

Bachelor of Science (Engr.) in Industrial and Production Engineering
Shahjalal University Of Science And Technology

Expected to complete in 2024

### **Work Experience**

April 2022 - Present **Kaggle Expert** Datasets Expert (Highest Rank : 96th of 64K+) Notebooks Expert (Highest Rank: 516th of 223K+) Discussion Expert (Highest Rank: 356th of 289K+) Sept. 2021 - Present Manager - BasaKhujo (Part time) Developing business development and financial strategy. Oversee R&D. Analyze about data, services, product, business intelligence. **Project Executive - 10 Minute School** (Part time) Mar 2022 - Present Content quality, performance and distribution analytics Started working here at Jun 2021 Team Lead, Content Design, 10 Minute School- Jobs Sep 2021 - Feb 2022 **Live-Class Resource Executive - Shikho** (Part time) Preparation and quality 500+ Live-Class materials. Content and performance analytics.

# **Projects and Works**

riojecis una works		
EDA Project	<ul> <li>Export Processing Zones – EDA + Statistical Analysis – URL</li> <li>A detailed exploratory data analysis of Export Processing Zones of BD with necessary Viz. Used pandas, seaborn, plotly, geopandas &amp; bokeh.</li> </ul>	
Tutorial Notebook	<ul> <li>Bias-Variance Tradeoff - Tutorial with NumPy &amp; Seaborn - URL</li> <li>A brief tutorial on Bias-Variance Tradeoff with visualization and explanations.</li> <li>Used pandas, numpy, seaborn, Scikitlearn to explain.</li> </ul>	
Prediction Model	Divorce   XGBoost   PCA Analysis with SHAP, TSNE - URL  An EDA of Divorce with necessary Viz. Predicted with XGBoost. Then, analyzed principal components. Used pandas, Numpy, seaborn, Xgboost, SHAP & Scikit-learn.	
Kaggle Dataset	<ul> <li>UCL 2021-22   Players Data   UEFA Champions League - URL</li> <li>Goals, Assists, Attack, Defense, Passing, Field Control, GK Data of UCL 2021-22.</li> <li>Collected by web scraping, with help of BeautifulSoup and pandas.</li> </ul>	
EDA & Viz Project	<ul> <li>Lionel Messi – Goals – Exploratory Data Analysis – URL</li> <li>A detailed exploratory data analysis of Lionel Messi – Club Goals with necessary Viz.</li> <li>Used numpy, pandas, seaborn, matplotlib.</li> </ul>	
Tutorial Notebook	<ul> <li>Intro to Imputation with Different Techniques - URL</li> <li>A brief tutorial on Imputation with 6 techniques and explanations.</li> <li>Used pandas, numpy, seaborn, Scikitlearn to explain.</li> </ul>	
Kaggle Dataset	<ul> <li>Cristiano Ronaldo   All Club Goals - URL</li> <li>Date, Time, Opponent, Match - All 698/+ Club Goal stats of Cristiano Ronaldo.</li> </ul>	

Gameloft | Android Games Data + Reviews - URL

Collected by web scraping, with help of Requests, BeautifulSoup, re and pandas

Reviews, Ratings, Installs, Size and all specs. of all Gameloft games. Used Pandas, BeautifulSoup, re, google\_play\_scraper, requests.

# Organizational/Voluntary Experience

Sep 2022 – Jan 2022 Started working here at Nov	Wing Director, Technical Facilities Enhancement – Black Brains
2020	Lead, Micro-course and App Product Development  Parameter is at PSD and increase and approximately account to the product Development.  Parameter is at PSD and increase and approximately account to the product Development.
2020	<ul> <li>Regular technical R&amp;D and improvements.</li> </ul>
Sep 2021 - Feb 2022	Judge, The Queen's Commonwealth Essay Competition 2021 – <i>Royal</i> Commonwealth Society
	<ul> <li>Member of the judging panel of the competition with 26,000+ submission</li> </ul>
Sep 2019 - Present	Online Volunteer - United Nations Volunteers
•	<ul> <li>Data, Translation, Design and consulting based projects</li> </ul>
Mar 2019 - Oct 2021	Information Technology Manager - Bangladesh Youngster Social
	Organization
	<ul> <li>Developed App, Website and other IT Structures for the organization and increased productivity by 350%.</li> </ul>

#### Other Skills

IT Automation, Software Troubleshooting, Advanced in IT and computer Skills Product Development, Project Management and Strategic Planning and Analysis. Microsoft Word - PowerPoint - Access, Google Tools, Communication, Team Management, Teamwork, Proficient in Bangla and English

#### Virtual Internships

Aug 2021	<ul> <li>Data Analytics Internship   EntryLevel</li> <li>Data Analytics , Business Modeling</li> <li>Used MS Excel, Power BI</li> </ul>
Jun 2021	<ul> <li>Engineering: Undergraduate &amp; Masters   Forage - Microsoft</li> <li>Software Engineering, Design, Engineering thinking</li> <li>Data Analytics , Business Modeling</li> </ul>
Mar 2021	<ul> <li>Data@ANZ Program   Forage - ANZ</li> <li>Data Science (Used Scikitlearn - Linear Regression)</li> <li>Exploratory Data Analysis - Predictive Analytics</li> </ul>
Apr 2021	<ul> <li>Open-Access Data Science &amp; Advanced Analytics Forage   BCG</li> <li>Data Science and Problem Structuring</li> <li>EDA, Feature Engineering, Mathematical Modeling</li> </ul>
	Prizes and Awards

GDN Presenta - Champion | Podiam 1.0 - 2nd Runners Up National High School Programming Contest – 2016 and 2017 – **Regional Winner; National Top 30 in both** Inter School & College Programming Contest '19 – **Regional (3<sup>rd</sup>) – National Top 30** Queens Commonwealth Essay Competition 2019 - Silver Award National Earth Science Olympiad 2019 - National Winner Bangladesh Physics Olympiad 2019 Comilla Region - 5th

# **Learning and Certifications**

# <u>Professional Certificates (Coursera):</u>

- DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer
- SAS Visual Business Analytics

#### Google Career - Professional Certificates (Coursera):

- Data Analyst
- IT Automation with Python
- IT Support Professional
- Project Management

#### **Edx Courses:**

- IBMx DS0105EN: Data Science Tools
- Harvardx PH526x: Using Python for Research

#### **Coursera Specializations Completed:**

- Python 3 Programming
- Applied Data Science with Python
- Data Analysis and Visualization

#### **DataCamp Learning Paths Completed:**

- Career Tracks: Python Programmer,
- Skill Tracks: Machine Learning Scientist with Python, Python Programming, Python **Fundamentals**
- Python *Advanced* Level Proficiency DataCamp Certified

#### **LinkedIn Learning Paths Completed:**

- Software Developer
- Data Analyst
- Financial Analyst

# IBM Developer Skills Network Programs:

- Data and AI CP4D Journey Intermediate
- Python for Data Science Program

#### Frecodecamp.org Certifications:

Data Analysis with Python